<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>T8G1-Skylab on Hosting, deployment and infrastructure services</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/</link><description>Recent content in T8G1-Skylab on Hosting, deployment and infrastructure services</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/about/</guid><description>Group T8G1
Project Assignment
62501 Linux Server and Network Course at DTU, spring 2022 edition.</description></item><item><title>Topology</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/topology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/topology/</guid><description>Topology
3. Topology We have now designed a sketch of our network topology, which can be seen in the picture above. In the diagram we show that we are hosting HUGO webserver in a docker container through subnet 10.81. We also used t8g1-ingress overlay network which has the benefits of automatically creating a subnet that of which, by our individual VM&amp;rsquo;s strict firewall rules See Security in section: nikolaj-vm, is isolated from the network and per docker&amp;rsquo;s generous trafic acceptance strategy as in: accepting anything and everything from anywhere to everywhere, effectively becomes a DMZ zone.</description></item><item><title>VM@Emin</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/emin-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/emin-vm/</guid><description>Unbound I want to implement an Unbound DNS in a container. Unbound is a recursive DNS resolver, which has the benefits of increasing online privacy. Furthermore, a user can encrypt communication because it supports DNS-over-HTTPS and DNS-over-TLS and unbound also makes sure that the data which is exchanged to the authoritative servers are limited. All this makes the DNS stronger which help to improve privacy. We want to use unbound because it is one of the best ways to secure a DNS server.</description></item><item><title>VM@Group</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/group-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/group-vm/</guid><description>Group VM Rootless docker Installing docker on our group vm requires carefull considerations regarding the security measure already implemented. If a rootless docker principle is not established on the docker host, any container running will have root privileges which isn&amp;rsquo;t really an issue for veteran sysadmins that knows have to restrict access to the docker daemon using aswell firewall or custom docker registries to allow only vetted and verified container images to run, but in the hands of non-experienced employee a non-rootless docker client will run any code within any docker image.</description></item><item><title>VM@Nikolaj</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/nikolaj-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/nikolaj-vm/</guid><description>Containers Apart from being the leading node and one of the two managers responsible for creating the custom overlay networks this host also participates in running one replica of the Hugo webservice distributed on the t8g1-ingress network. One standalone container running in host mode supplies a local registry which purpose is to ensure a higher level of network integrity by allowing only a subset of container images to be deployed throughout all docker nodes.</description></item><item><title>VM@Saif</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/saif-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realnikolaj.github.io/t8g1-skylab/saif-vm/</guid><description>Docker worker node Hugo task service
Jira Container In my personal vm i want to set up a jira container Since we want to be a hosting, deployment and infrastructure service, it would be essential to have a tool to help us with managing our projects. Jira is basically a ticket managing software, which will help us delegate work and help us with bug tracking. To set it up it will be as simple as to use the jiras docker image (I hope)</description></item></channel></rss>