<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Danish Legislation analysis on Visualisation, analysis and NLP of Danish legislation</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/</link><description>Recent content in Danish Legislation analysis on Visualisation, analysis and NLP of Danish legislation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/about/</guid><description>Group 6
Project Assignment
02467 Computational Social Science Course at DTU, spring 2022 edition.</description></item><item><title>Conclusion and Future perspectives</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/future-perspectives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/future-perspectives/</guid><description>Conclusion We were able to identify laws that have high impact on the legislative body concerning the period of the Corona virus pandemic, with text and network analysis centrality measures. The top 3 laws identified:
1: Bekendtgørelse af kildeskatteloven: 2: Lov om ændring af tinglysningsafgiftsloven og forskellige andre love og om ophævelse af lov om afgift af antibiotika og vækstfremmere anvendt i foderstoffer (Afgiftssaneringspakke m.v.): 3: Lov om ændring af registreringsafgiftsloven og forskellige andre love (Styrket regelefterlevelse på motorområdet, skærpet bødepraksis ved overtrædelse af registreringsafgiftsloven og øvrige punktafgiftslove og øvrige tilpasninger af reglerne på motorområdet) Law nr.</description></item><item><title>Data description</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/data-description/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/data-description/</guid><description>Data presented on this site consists of a collection of documents produced by the various Danish governments and ministeries and hosted on the public website www.retsinformation.dk. Each node in the following networks represents a unique document regarding procedures and contents of ammending, changing or adding laws in Denmark. There are various instances or government bodies capable of producing these documents thus each document contains information such as the body initializing the proposal of said new document, date of creation, ID&amp;rsquo;s etc.</description></item><item><title>Network analysis</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/graphbuilder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/graphbuilder/</guid><description>import pandas as pd import networkx as nx import bz2 import pickle import _pickle as cPickle data = bz2.BZ2File(&amp;#39;../data/picl_data.pbz2&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;rb&amp;#39;) data = cPickle.load(data) data = data.head(30) #This is maybe redundant def getIdFromUrl(url): try: id = url.split(&amp;#34;lta/&amp;#34;) if (len(id) == 1): id = url.split(&amp;#34;ft/&amp;#34;) if (len(id) == 1): id = url.split(&amp;#34;ltb/&amp;#34;) id = id[1] except: print(&amp;#34;error getting id from. &amp;#34;, url) return -1 #May be bad return id Create graph G = nx.</description></item><item><title>Network analysis</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/network-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/network-analysis/</guid><description>Brief basis of the network:
Each node is unique and represents either: A) A law or amendment to another law and is currently effective or B) A passed proposal going into effect some time in the future Edges are directional and originates from law documents by: A) Being based on referrences to other documents e.g. to a specific law document or a paragraph within a law that would provide the necessary legal foundation for where the edge originated and/or providing eseential background definitions regarding the scope of the law B) Being based on the fact that a law is to some extent ammending or adding new definitions to other laws.</description></item><item><title>Text analysis</title><link>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/text-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realnikolaj.github.io/G6_Retsinformation/text-analysis/</guid><description>In order to understand the data, one needs to understand the content. To present the law text it in a concise mannerWordclouds will be used to quickly grasp what the content of the law is about.
Text processing To represent the large body of text in the laws with only the most meaningful words in a wordcloud, the text was processed in the following workflow:
Remove formatting, punctuation and numbers.</description></item></channel></rss>